Guide to the George Harmon Coxe Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
George Harmon Coxe papers
1897-1980
1920-1980
YCAL MSS 556
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
33.27
(81 boxes)
This collection consists of material created and accumulated by George Harmon Coxe in the course of his career as a crime novelist and short story writer. Material includes writings, correspondence, financial papers, subject files, photographs, printed material and scrapbooks by or relating to George Harmon Coxe, spanning the years 1897 to 1980, with the bulk of the material spanning 1922 to 1980.
Coxe, George Harmon, 1901-1984
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of George Harmon Coxe, 1965-1979. Gift of J. Randolph Cox, 1973. Gift of Janet Coxe Davis, 1997.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Box 79: Restricted Fragile Material. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of material created and accumulated by George Harmon Coxe in the course of his career as a crime novelist and short story writer. Material includes writings, correspondence, financial papers, subject files, photographs, printed material and scrapbooks by or relating to George Harmon Coxe, spanning the years 1897 to 1980, with the bulk of the material spanning 1922 to 1980.
Arrangement
Organized into two groupings: I. 1965-1979 Acquisitions II. October 1997 Acquisition.
Material within this collection has been organized by acquisition reflecting the fact that the collection has been acquired in increments over time.
Researchers should note that material within each acquisition overlaps with/or relates to material found in other acquisitions. For instance, correspondence and writings can be found in both groupings. In order to locate all relevant material within this collection, researchers will need to consult each acquisition described in the Collection Contents section.
George Harmon Coxe (1901-1984)
George Harmon Coxe, American novelist, was born in 1901 in Olean, New York. He attended Purdue University from 1919-1920 and Cornell University from 1920-1921. Coxe worked as a reporter in San Diego and New York and as an advertising salesman in Massachusetts. Coxe married Elizabeth Fowler in 1929 and they had one daughter and one son.
During the course of his career as a crime and detective novelist, Coxe authored over 60 books and numerous short stories published in magazines such as Black Mask, Street & Smith's Detective Story Magazine, and Cosmopolitan. Two films were made from Coxe's stories: Women Are Trouble was released in 1936 and Here's Flash Casey in 1938. Coxe was awarded the Mystery Writers of America Grand Master award in 1964. He died January 30, 1984 in Hilton Head Island, South Carolina.
Authors, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Detective and mystery stories, American -- 20th Century; Photographic prints; Authors -- United States -- 20th Century; Coxe, George Harmon, 1901-1984
- 1965-1979 Acquisitions, 1937-1972; Series I; 13.13; (32 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Organized into three series: Writings, Correspondence, and Brandt & Brandt Files. Writings are arranged alphabetically by title. Correspondence is arranged alphabetically by name. Brandt & Brandt files are arranged chronologically.
  Scope and Contents
  Writings consist of typescript, and typescript carbon drafts, often with the author's corrections or editorial markup, and proofs. Correspondence consists of incoming letters from Coxe's publishers, family, and friends; some third-party letters are enclosed. The Brandt & Brandt files contain business correspondence between Coxe's publisher and third parties, consisting mostly of original incoming letters and carbons of outgoing letters, and relating to Coxe's works.
  General note
  Formerly classed as Za Coxe and Uncat Za Ms Coxe.
  - Writings, 1937-1972
    - An Easy Way to Go
      - Setting typescript, circa 1969 (Box 80)
      - Page proof, circa 1969 (Box 80)
    - The Big Gamble, typescript, corrected, 1958 (Box 1)
    - The Camera Clue, typescript (carbon), corrected, 1937 (Box 1)
    - The Candid Impostor
      - Setting typescript, corrected, undated (Box 1)
      - Galley proofs, corrected, undated (Box 1)
      - Page proof, corrected, undated (Box 2)
      - Plate proof, undated (Box 2)
    - The Crimson Clue
      - Typescript (carbon), corrected, 1952 (Box 2)
      - Page proof, corrected, 1952 (Box 2)
      - Final galley proof, 1952 (Box 2)
      - Foundry proof, 1952 (Box 3)
      - Final plate proof, 1952 (Box 3)
    - Deadly Image, typescript, corrected, 1964 (Box 3)
    - Death at the Isthmus, typescript (carbon), 1954 (Box 3)
    - Double Identity
      - Setting typescript, corrected, undated (Box 4)
      - First proof (computer print-out), corrected, undated (Box 4)
      - Final proof, pasted up as dummy, corrected, undated (Box 4)
    - Error of Judgment
      - Typescript, corrected, 1961 (Box 4)
      - Typescript (carbon), corrected, 1961 (Box 5)
      - Final galley proof, 1961 (Box 5)
      - Page proof, corrected, 1961 (Box 5)
    - Fenner
      - Setting typescript, corrected, 1971 (Box 5)
      - Proofs, 1971 (Box 5)
      - Proofs, 1971 (Box 6)
    - Focus on Murder
      - Typescript, corrected, 1954 (Box 6)
      - Typescript (carbon), corrected, 1954 (Box 6)
    - Four Frightened Women, typescript, corrected, 1939 (Box 7)
    - The Hidden Key, typescript, corrected., 1963 (Box 7)
      Includes typed notes by the author concerning the characters and plot.
    - The Impetuous Mistress, typescript, corrected, 1958 (Box 7)
    - The Inside Man
      - Typescript, corrected, 1972 (Box 80)
      - Setting typescript, 1972 (Box 80)
    - The Lady Is Afraid, typescript, corrected, 1940 (Box 8)
    - Lady Killer, typescript (carbon), 1949 (Box 9)
    - The Last Commandment, typescript, corrected, 1960 (Box 9)
    - Man on a Rope, typescript (carbon), corrected, 1956 (Box 9)
    - The Man Who Died Too Soon, typescript, corrected, 1962 (Box 9)
      Includes notes by the author concerning the characters and plot.
    - The Man Who Died Twice
      - Typescript (carbon), corrected, 1951 (Box 10)
      - Author's galley proof, corrected, 1951 (Box 10)
      - Author's page proof, 1951 (Box 10)
    - Mission of Fear, typescript, corrected, 1962 (Box 11)
      Includes notes by the author concerning characters and plot.
    - Moment of Violence, typescript, corrected, 1961 (Box 11)
    - Murder for the Asking
      - Typescript, corrected, 1939 (Box 11)
      - Typescript (carbon), corrected, 1939 (Box 12)
    - Murder On Their Minds
      - Typescript, corrected, 1957 (Box 12)
      - Typescript (carbon), corrected, 1957 (Box 12)
    - Never Bet Your Life
      - Typescript, corrected, 1952 (Box 12)
      - Page Proof, corrected, 1952 (Box 13)
    - No Place for Murder, setting typescript, corrected, undated (Box 13)
    - One Hour to Kill
      - Typescript, corrected, 1963 (Box 13)
      - Final galley proof, corrected, 1963 (Box 13)
    - One Minute Past Eight, typescript, corrected, 1957 (Box 14)
    - One Way Out, typescript, corrected, 1960 (Box 14)
    - The Reluctant Heiress
      - Setting typescript, corrected, undated (Box 14)
      - Original galley proof, corrected, undated (Box 14)
      - Final galley proof, corrected, undated (Box 15)
      - Page proofs, corrected, undated (Box 15)
      - Foundry proofs, corrected, undated (Box 15)
    - The Ring of Truth
      - Setting typescript, corrected, undated (Box 15)
      - Final galley proof, corrected, undated (Box 15)
      - Page proofs, corrected, undated; 2 (Box 16)
    - Silent Are the Dead, typescript, corrected, 1942 (Box 16)
    - The Silent Witness
      - Typescript, circa 1974 (Box 81)
      - Galley proof, circa 1974 (Box 81)
      - Page proofs, circa 1974; 2 (Box 81)
    - Slack Tide, typescript, corrected, 1959 (Box 16)
      Original title: "The Shuttered Room."
    - Suddenly a Widow
      - Typescript, corrected, 1956 (Box 17)
      - Typescript (carbon), corrected, 1956 (Box 17)
      - Page proof, with four leaves of foundry proof, corrected, 1956 (Box 17)
      - Final galley proof, corrected, 1956 (Box 17)
    - Top Assignment, typescript (carbon), 1955 (Box 18)
    - Triple Exposure
      - Galley proof, corrected, 1959 (Box 18)
      - Page proof, corrected, 1959 (Box 18)
    - The Widow Had a Gun
      - Typescript, corrected, 1951 (Box 19)
      - Galley proof, 1951 (Box 19)
      - Author's page proof, corrected, 1951 (Box 19)
    - With Intent to Kill
      - Typescript, corrected, 1965 (Box 20)
        Includes notes concerning characters and plot.
      - Typescript, corrected, 1965 (Box 20)
      - Final galley proof, corrected, 1965 (Box 20)
      - Page proof, 1965 (Box 20)
      - Foundry proof, 1965 (Box 21)
    - Woman With a Gun, setting typescript, corrected, 1972 (Box 21)
  - Correspondence, 1939-1959
    - Blassingame, Lurton (Box 22)
    - Brandt & Brandt, 1939-1957; 8 (Box 22)
    - Brandt & Brandt, 1958-1959; 2 (Box 23)
    - Chandler, Raymond (Box 23)
    - CBS (Box 23)
    - Cornell (Box 23)
    - Knopf, Alfred A., Inc., 1939-1959; 6 (Box 23)
    - Margulies & Heit (Box 23)
    - Markey, Morris (Box 23)
    - Mystery Writers of America (Box 23)
    - Nebel, Frederick (Box 23)
    - Phillips Exeter Academy (Box 23)
    - Sanders & Conroy (Box 24)
    - Speckled Band of Boston (Box 24)
    - Walsh, Thomas (Box 24)
    - White, Kenneth S. (Box 24)
    - The Writer (Box 24)
    - Unsorted correspondence, royalties and contracts, 5 (Box 24)
    - Unsorted correspondence with publishers, 1939-1959; 12 (Box 25)
  - Brandt & Brandt Files, 1940-1967
    - Brandt & Brandt files, 1940-1947; 8 (Box 26)
    - Brandt & Brandt files, 1948-1951; 8 (Box 27)
    - Brandt & Brandt files, 1952-1955; 8 (Box 28)
    - Brandt & Brandt files, 1956-1960; 9 (Box 29)
    - Brandt & Brandt files, 1961-1967; 8 (Box 30)
- October 1997 Acquisition, 1897-1980; 2; 20.14; (49 boxes)
  Organized into five series: Writings, Writings of Others, Correspondence, Photographs, and Other Papers. Other Papers are further organized into four subseries: Financial Papers, Subject Files, Printed Material, and Personal Papers and Other Material.
  Writings consist primarily of original typescript and typescript carbon drafts of novels, short stories, essays, plays, screenplays, and radio plays by Coxe. Some proofs, notes, character sketches, plot outlines and other related material are also contained in the series. Writings of others is a small group of material consisting primarily of adaptations of Coxe's stories for radio and television. Correspondence is comprised of incoming personal and professional letters and enclosures. Photographs are of George Harmon Coxe and others, with some photographs of Coxe's home and travels. Other Papers contain financial papers including contracts and royalty statements; subject files of assorted personal papers; printed material, which includes newspaper clipppings, magazines and other publications in which Coxe's works are published, and assorted ephemera; and personal and other papers, which are mostly unsorted and unidentified material.
  Formerly classed as Uncat ZA MS 538.
  - Writings, 1931-1965
    - Alias the Killer, short story, typescript, original, annotated, 1944 (Box 31)
    - Alias the Killer, short story, typescript, carbon, undated (Box 31)
    - Alias the Killer, short story, typescript, carbon, annotated, undated (Box 31)
    - All Routes Delivered, short story, typescript, carbon [Published in Coronet?], undated (Box 31)
    - Assignment in Guiana, novel, typescript, original, corrected, circa 1941; 4 (Box 31)
    - Anniversary Present, short story, typescript, carbon, undated (Box 31)
    - Bad Medicine, short story, typescript, carbon, annotated and corrected, undated (Box 31)
    - The Barotique Mystery, novel, typescript, carbon, annotated by the author, undated; 4 (Box 31)
    - Barry's Boast, short story, typescript, original, with author's corrections, undated (Box 31)
    - Barry's Boast, short story, typescript, original, undated (Box 31)
    - Barry's Boast, short story, typescript, carbon, undated (Box 31)
    - The Black Box, short story, typescript, carbon, annotated [Published in Thrilling Detective?], 1933 (Box 31)
    - Blackmail Incorporated, short story, typescript, carbon, annotated, 1934 (Box 31)
    - Blind Date, short story, typescript, carbon, undated (Box 31)
    - The Bungalow Murders, chapter outline, typescript, original, annotated by the author, undated (Box 31)
    - The Bungalow Murders, character synopsis, typescript, original, annotated by the author, undated (Box 31)
    - The Bungalow Murders, outline, typescript, original, annotated by the author, undated (Box 31)
    - The Camera Clue, chapter outline, typescript, original, corrected by the author, undated (Box 32)
    - The Camera Clue, character synopsis, typescript, original, corrected by the author, undated (Box 32)
    - The Camera Clue, outline, typescript, original, corrected by the author, undated (Box 32)
    - Candlewood Lake Murder, synopsis, typescript, original, undated (Box 32)
    - Candlewood Lake Murder, synopsis, typescript, carbon, revised draft, undated (Box 32)
    - Captain Caution, short story, typescript, carbon, annotated and corrected [Published in the Saturday Evening Post ?], undated (Box 32)
    - Case of the Careless Killer, synopsis, typescript, carbon, undated (Box 32)
    - Casey (Crime Photographer), outline for a television series, typescript, original, corrected, 1957 (Box 32)
    - Casey (Crime Photographer), outline for a television series, typescript, carbon, 1957 August 24 (Box 32)
    - Cashing in on Washington's Birthday, essay, typescript, original, annotated by the author, undated (Box 32)
    - The Category is Murder, television script, typescript, mimeograph, revised draft, 1957 October 21; 3 (Box 32)
    - Cause for Suspicion, short story, typescript, carbon, undated (Box 32)
    - Cause for Suspicion, short story, typescript, carbon, annotated, and corrected [Published in Liberty?], undated (Box 32)
    - Cape Cod Dairy Cottage for Department Store, essay, typescript, original, annotated, and corrected, signed, undated (Box 32)
    - Cape Cod Dairy Cottage for Department Stores, typescript, carbon, annotated [Published in Dry Goods Economist?], undated (Box 32)
    - Character and the Mystery [Story?], essay, typescript, carbon, annotated[Published in The Writer?], 1959 (Box 32)
    - The Charred Witness, proof, introductory material, 1942 April 28 (Box 32)
    - Circumstantial Evidence, short story, typescript, carbon, annotated [Published in Liberty?], 1949 September (Box 32)
    - Citation for a Sailor, short story, typescript, carbon, annotated [Published in Cosmic?], undated (Box 32)
    - A Clever Imitation, short story, typescript, carbon, annotated [Published in Clues?], undated (Box 32)
    - The Cliffwood Case, chapter outline, typescript, original, annotated by the author, undated (Box 32)
    - The Cliffwood Case, character synopsis, typescript, original, undated (Box 32)
    - The Cliffwood Case, outline, typescript, original, annotated by the author, undated (Box 32)
    - Conspiracy, short story, typescript, carbon, annotated [Published in American Magazine?], undated (Box 32)
    - Contraband, short story, typescript, carbon, annotated [Published in Super Detective?], 1933 (Box 32)
    - Counter-Evidence, short story, typescript, carbon, annotated [Published in Detective Fiction Weekly?], undated (Box 32)
    - Counter-Plot, short story, typescript, carbon, annotated [Published in American Magazine as Intelligence from the Reich.], 1942 (Box 32)
    - Courage Isn't Everything, short story, typescript, carbon, undated (Box 32)
    - Courage Isn't Everything, short story, typescript, carbon, annotated [Published in Collier's?], 1944 July 17 (Box 32)
    - The Crab Maker, short story, typescript, carbon, undated; 2 (Box 32)
    - The Crimson Seal, chapter outlines, typescript, original, annotated, and corrected by the author, undated (Box 32)
    - The Crimson Seal, character synopsis, typescript, original, corrected by the author, 1938 December 2 (Box 32)
    - The Crimson Seal, outline, typescript, original, annotated by the author, undated (Box 32)
    - Cyclops, short story, typescript, carbon, annotated, undated (Box 32)
    - The Dead Can't Hide, short story, typescript, carbon, annotated [Published in Detective Fiction Weekly?], 1935 (Box 33)
    - Deadly Acquittal, short story, typescript, carbon [Published in Magazine Publishers?], 1936 June (Box 33)
    - The Death Club, short story, typescript, carbon, annotated, 1933 December 15 (Box 33)
    - Death by Proxy, short story, typescript, carbon, annotated [Published in Super Detective?], 1933 (Box 33)
    - Delayed Death, short story, typescript, carbon, annotated [Published in Dime Detective?], 1934 (Box 33)
    - The Diamond Murders, short story, typescript, carbon, annotated [Published in Dime Detective?], 1934 (Box 33)
    - The Doctor Takes a Case, short story, typescript, original, undated (Box 33)
    - The Doctor Takes a Case, short story, typescript, carbon, annotated [Published in Liberty as Post Mortem, 2c.], undated (Box 33)
    - Dr. Standish - Audition Script, typescript, original, corrected, 1948 (Box 33)
    - Dr. Standish - Audition Script, typescript, carbon, 1948 April 29 (Box 33)
    - Dr. Standish, Medical Examiner ..., radio script, typescript, mimeograph, annotated, 1948 July 1 (Box 33)
    - Double or Nothing, short story, typescript, carbon, undated (Box 33)
    - The Dune Murders, short story, typescript, carbon, annotated [Published in Thrilling Detective?], 1934 (Box 33)
    - Dynamite, story outline, typescript, original, annotated, and signed, undated (Box 33)
    - Easy Money, short story, typescript, carbon, annotated, 1933 December 15 (Box 33)
    - The Education of Johnny Burke, [Marathons are Different], short story, typescript, original, annotated, and corrected, first draft [Published in The Saturday Evening Post?], undated (Box 33)
    - End of the Line, script, typescript, carbon, undated (Box 33)
    - Even Up, short story, typescript, carbon, 1933 (Box 33)
    - Even Up, short story, typescript, carbon, annotated, and corrected [Published in Thrilling Detective?], 1933 (Box 33)
    - Eye Witness, short story, typescript, carbon, annotated [Published in American Magazine?], undated (Box 33)
    - Face Value, short story, typescript, carbon, annotated, and corrected, undated (Box 34)
    - Fall Guy, short story, typescript, carbon, undated (Box 34)
    - Fashioned for Murder, novel, author's proof, with author's corrections, undated (Box 34)
    - Fashioned for Murder, novel, author's proof, with author's corrections, 1947 February 20 (Box 34)
    - Fifteen a Week, short story, typescript, carbon, annotated, and corrected [Published in Detective Fiction Weekly?], undated (Box 34)
    - The Fifth Key, chapter outline, typescript, original, annotated by the author, undated (Box 34)
    - The Fifth Key, character outline, typescript, original, corrected by the author, undated (Box 34)
    - The Fifth Key, novel, typescript, carbon, undated (Box 34)
    - The Fifth Key, novel, Chapters 1-23, original, with printer's corrections, 1947; 5 (Box 34)
    - The Fifth Key, novel, miscellaneous proofs, with author's corrections, circa 1946 (Box 35)
    - The Fifth Key, novel, author's first proof, with author's corrections, 1946 October 2 (Box 35)
    - The Fifth Key, novel, author's first proof, with author's corrections, 1946 October 23 (Box 35)
    - The Fifth Key, novel, author's second proof, with author's corrections, 1946 (Box 35)
    - Final Appeal, short story, typescript, carbon, annotated [Published in Detective Fiction Weekly?], 1934 (Box 35)
    - Fisherman's Luck, short story, typescript, carbon, annotated [Published in Open Road?], 1933 May (Box 35)
    - The Flapper, poem, typescript, carbon, undated (Box 35)
    - For Acquittal, short story, typescript, original, annotated, 1934 (Box 35)
    - For Services Rendered, short story, typescript, carbon, annotated [Published in Argosy?], undated (Box 35)
    - A Forward, essay, typescript, carbon, annotated, and corrected by the author, 1954 March 18 (Box 35)
    - Fortress of Doom, short story, typescript, carbon, annotated, 1936 (Box 35)
    - [ The Frightened Fiancee ?], novel, Chapters 1-23, typescript, carbon, corrected, undated; 3 (Box 35)
    - A Full Gold Stripe, short story, typescript, carbon [Published in The Saturday Evening Post?], undated (Box 35)
    - A Full Gold Stripe, short story, typescript, carbon [Published in the Saturday Evening Post?], undated (Box 35)
    - Full Payment, short story, typescript, carbon, annotated, and corrected [Published in Argosy?], 1933 (Box 35)
    - Getting Phil a Girl, short story, typescript, original, undated (Box 36)
    - Getting Phil a Girl, short story, typescript, carbon, undated (Box 36)
    - Girl Wanted, short story, typescript, carbon, annotated [Published in Colliers?], undated (Box 36)
    - The Groom Lay Dead, chapter outline, typescript, original, annotated by the author, undated (Box 36)
    - The Groom Lay Dead, novel, typescript, carbon, annotated, undated (Box 36)
    - Headwork, short story, typescript, carbon [Published in Magazine Publishers?], 1936 (Box 36)
    - The Hollow Needle, chapter outline, typescript, original, annotated by the author, undated (Box 36)
    - The Hollow Needle, character outline, typescript, original, corrected, undated (Box 36)
    - Hot Assignment, short story, typescript, carbon, annotated [Published in Clues?], 1934 June 15 (Box 36)
    - Hot Hunches, short story, typescript, carbon, annotated, and corrected [Published in Clues?], undated (Box 36)
    - Hot Delivery, short story, typescript, carbon, annotated [Published in Black Mask?], undated (Box 36)
    - I Thought I'd Die, [Four Frightened Women], novel, Chapters 1-23, typescript, carbon, with author's corrections, undated; 4 (Box 36)
    - I Thought I'd Die, novel, Chapters 1-12, typescript, carbon, undated; 2 (Box 36)
    - I Thought I'd Die, novel, Chapters 13-23, typescript, carbon, undated; 2 (Box 37)
    - I Thought I'd Die, novel, p. 84a-198 only, typescript, carbon, corrected, undated (Box 37)
    - The Ideal Girl, short story, typescript, carbon, undated (Box 37)
    - The Impetuous Mistress, novel, typescript, original, and carbon, corrected, 1956-1957 (Box 37)
    - In a Frenzied Moment, short story, typescript, carbon, undated (Box 37)
    - In Real Life, short story, typescript, carbon, undated (Box 37)
    - [Inside Passage?], chapter outline, typescript, original, annotated by the author, undated (Box 37)
    - [Inside Passage?], plot outline, typescript, original, corrected, undated (Box 37)
    - Introduction to the Dry Little Sticks, essay, typescript, carbon, annotated by the author, undated (Box 37)
    - It Pays to be Neat, short story, typescript, carbon [Published in Ellery Queen's Mystery Magazine?], undated (Box 37)
    - It's Teamwork That Counts, typescript, carbon, annotated, 1934 (Box 37)
    - Jack (Flashgun) Casey, essay, typescript, carbon, corrected by the author, undated (Box 37)
    - The Jade Venus, chapter outline, typescript, original, annotated by the author, undated (Box 37)
    - The Jade Venus, character outlines, typescript, original, annotated by the author, undated (Box 37)
    - The Jade Venus, novel, typescript, carbon, undated (Box 37)
    - Jailed, short story, typescript, carbon, annotated [Published in Thrilling Detective?], 1934 May (Box 37)
    - Johnny Get Your Gun, short story, typescript, carbon, undated (Box 37)